<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Capybara | Passionate coding]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.yux.ch/blog/categories/capybara/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.yux.ch/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-02T01:16:15+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.yux.ch/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Raffael Schmid]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Javascript tests with PhantomJS]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.yux.ch/blog/2013/01/19/javascript-tests-with-phantomjs/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-19T17:57:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.yux.ch/blog/2013/01/19/javascript-tests-with-phantomjs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I wanted to write some javascript tests for my <a href="https://github.com/luxflux/Moviez">Moviezz</a> project.</p>

<p>Maybe two years ago, I've written javascript tests for a project at <a href="http://nine.ch">nine.ch</a>.
I ended up by using Cucumber, Capybara and Selenium for this. The result was okay, but it took you a very long time to run the tests
and you could not do anything else than watching your webbrowser clicking links and filling in text.</p>

<p>Some weeks ago, I heard about PhantomJS and I waited since for the right chance to try it out.
PhantomJS enables you to run your javascript tests headless, means no browser windows is opened and used to click and fill.
This also gives you the ability to run your javascript tests via Jenkins or Travis.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>At first, I verified that <code>capybara</code> is in my <code>Gemfile</code>.</p>

<p><code>ruby Gemfile
gem 'capybara', group: :test
</code></p>

<p>It also has to be loaded by <code>RSpec</code>, so I required it in <code>spec_helper</code>.
<code>ruby spec/spec_helper.rb
require 'capybara/rspec'
require 'capybara/rails'
</code></p>

<p>After this, I went on and wrote the first javascript test with RSpec.
Note the <code>js: true</code> on line 7, this switches the Capybara driver to the javascript adapter.</p>

<p>```ruby spec/integration/search_movie_spec.rb
require 'spec_helper'</p>

<p>describe 'search for a movie' do</p>

<p>  let(:tmdb_movie) { tmdb_result }</p>

<p>  it 'searches for the given title', js: true do</p>

<pre><code>visit new_movie_path
page.should_not have_content('Star Wars Episode VII')
fill_in 'title', with: 'Star Wars'
page.should have_content('Star Wars Episode VII')
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<p>When I ran the test, Capybara opened a new Firefox window and did my defined steps as expected.</p>

<p>To use PhantomJS with Capybara, you have to switch to another adapter.
There is an adapter called Poltergeist which enables you to use PhantomJS.
So I went on and added Poltergeist to my Gemfile.</p>

<p><code>ruby Gemfile
gem 'poltergeist', group: :test
</code></p>

<p>As soon as I required <code>capybara/poltergeist</code> and added <code>Capybara.javascript_driver = :poltergeist</code> in <code>spec_helper.rb</code>, my javascript test passed without opening a window.</p>

<p>You cannot use transactions, which is the default, to cleanup your database after each javascript test, better explained <a href="https://github.com/jnicklas/capybara#transactions-and-database-setup">here</a>.
To solve this, you can use <code>DatabaseCleaner</code> with the truncation strategy instead of transactions.</p>

<p>But there is a caveat, the truncation strategy is slower.
As I like my tests run fast, I wrote the following RSpec configuration which just enables the truncation strategy
for tests with <code>js: true</code> set.</p>

<p>```ruby spec/support/javascript.rb
RSpec.configure do |config|</p>

<p>  config.before :suite do</p>

<pre><code>DatabaseCleaner.strategy = :transaction
DatabaseCleaner.clean_with :truncation
Capybara.javascript_driver = :poltergeist
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  config.before :each do</p>

<pre><code>if example.metadata[:js]
  DatabaseCleaner.strategy = :truncation
else
  DatabaseCleaner.strategy = :transaction
  DatabaseCleaner.start
end
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  config.after :each do</p>

<pre><code>DatabaseCleaner.clean
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>end
```</p>

<p>Note, that I also moved <code>Capybara.javascript_driver = :poltergeist</code> into this config file as it belongs to the javascript configuration.</p>

<p>After this, I just had to disable the default transactional feature in <code>spec_helper.rb</code>
<code>ruby spec_helper.rb
RSpec.configure do |config|
  config.use_transactional_fixtures = false
end
</code></p>

<p>Now, I have headless javascript tests and the fastest possible database cleanup strategy depending on the test type.</p>

<p>All the code above can also be found <a href="https://gist.github.com/4573914">in a gist</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
